We're going to show you some of the different techniques for applying vehicle graphics and decals.
At this time, I'm going to show you how to do the center hinge wet application method.
First, before you actually apply it, you want to find the center mark of the roof of the are that you're going to mark.
Lay your vinyl on here, measure it up.
I measured from the top of the back of the window to a center mark, so it's centered where I want it.
Then you want to take your tape and make a mark.
This mark being the center hinge area.
You simply want to peel it off, thus making the hinge method.
With the hinge method, it's best to start from the side of the center line that you don't have any vinyl there on the tape.
Therefore, I'll start on this side with the 28.
You want to pick the tape up, pull away the masking from the vinyl.
At which point, you'll come in and tear the protective backing off.
Take your application fluid, get it nice and wet.
Lay the vinyl back over and take your squeegee.
Firmly press the vinyl down to secure the area.
In doing this, this will take all the excess water out from underneath the masking tape.
Once you get this side down, you want to take the tape off the other side. Take the second piece of tape off that you used for your hinge.
Now that you have this side, this acts as your hinge.
You want to peel this tape off, apply your application fluid, and again always squeegee from the hinge or the tape line out.
Once you have it squeegeed, you can simply take your masking slowly peeling it way, keeping it as close to the masking as possible.
As you see here, I peeled the letter up because of the moisture underneath it.
Simply take your squeegee with the felt side and squeegee it back down.
Make sure you apply firm pressure across all of it, removing any water bubbles.
Now you have applied using the center hinge wet method application.